MADELEINE MILASAS SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Hi I'm Maddi, a software engineer from Sydney. I love unpacking problems and using data to develop compelling customer experiences. I'm passionate about creating with code - with a background in television, film & live performance technology, I love innovation and harnessing the power of combining creativity with technical skill.

EXPERIENCE

Developer

Ansarada Apr 2018 - Oct 2020

Front and back-end development (React & .NET) for virtual data room provider Ansarada. Collaborating with cross-functional agile teams, I built and maintained customer features, improved engineering processes, led modules & devised full-stack implementation plans, and loved wiring up integrations to understand customer behaviours and engineering improvements using data. I also drove community initiatives such as study groups and mentoring aspiring developers.

3 x winner of company-wide hackathons (3 out of 3 entries)

Master Control Operator, Media Operator

Deluxe MediaCloud 2015 - 2018

Video, audio & communication signal control & manipulation for SBS's suite of channels, with high-profile broadcasts such as Eurovision Song Contest, Tour de France, UEFA Champions League, Aust. & US elections

Lighting Technician

Production Resource Group (USA) 2015

Media Operator, Media Manager, Studio Technical Director

SBS Television 2012 - 2015

Twice awarded company-wide excellence (GEM) award

Interaction Designer

The Digital Shamans Contract-based, 2013 & 2014

Design, programming & implementation of interactive multimedia installations, inc. 'Dichroic Dimensions', Vivid Sydney 2014, MCA facade

Film/TV Data Wrangler Film/TV/Events Production Coordinator

Freelance Contract-based, 2010 - 2012

Visual Effects Artist

The Lab Sydney 2008 - 2010

Feature film & TV visual effects for titles such as 'Tomorrow When The War Began' and 'Australia'

3 AACTA Awards for Best Visual Effects

Independent Video Production

2007 - 2009

Producer, 1st AD, Post-Production Supervisor for music video production

Winner IF Award 2008; Nominee IF Award 2009; Nominee ARIA Award 2008; Nominee J Award 2008

Post-Production Coordinator, Tape Operator

2005 - 2008

PORTFOLIO + CONTACT

www.madeleinemilasas.com

0421 644 469

maddi.milasas@gmail.com

O Dual AUS / EU Citizenship

in/madeleine-milasas

github.com/madeleinemila

SKILLS

WEB

JavaScript inc React, Redux, GraphQL, Node, Flow HTML5, CSS3 .NET, Ruby on Rails Haskell. ReasonML

I ALSO LIKE USING

Ableton Live, Arduino, Processing, Photoshop, Premiere Pro

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, 2018

Grad. Diploma of Interaction Design & Electronic Arts

University of Sydney, 2014

Yhigh Distinction Average

Bachelor of Arts (Film Studies, Media & Communications)

University of Sydney, 2008

REFERENCES

Ben Meneses-Sosa

VP of Engineering - Ansarada

Joel Morland

Team Lead - Ansarada

Giustina Salvestro-Booth

Product Manager - Ansarada

Contact details available on request

The Lab Sydney